Will Gallia

Contact wgallia@gmail.com

http://wgallia.com +447944137483 29 Benyon Wharf 295 Kingsland Road E8 4DQ

Profile

I am a 23 year programmer living in London. I was brought up in Turkey, schooled in Bristol and spent a year in Manchester before coming to London, where I pursued an education in Computing, focusing on the creative possibilities of programming.

EXPERIENCE

Swanlea School, Whitechapel, London

Assistant Teacher

03.2011 - 04.2011

As part of the TDAs Student Associate scheme, I worked along side teachers in both the Science and Maths departments.

greyworld, London

Computer Programmer

07.2010 - 09.2010

As a summer job, I programmed real-time generative visuals for London based art collective greyworld. During this project I worked alongside greyworld's founder, Andrew Shoben and advertising agency Ogilvy, programming their ideas.

Dursley Swimming Pool and Sports Centre, Gloucestershire

Lifeguard

07.2007 - 01.2008

After qualifying as a Lifeguard I worked for 6 months at my local pool. While working I was trusted with the public's safety.

${\bf Capone's\ Nightclub},\ {\bf Dursley},\ {\bf Gloucestershire}$

Bartender

07.2007 - 07.2008

At this nightclub I served a variety of drinks and cocktails.

EDUCATION

Goldsmiths Collge, London

BSc Creative Computing

09.2009 - 05.2012

First Class Honours, final average: 84%

Manchester University, Manchester

BEng Chemical Engineering

09.2008 - 04.2009

Two semesters completed

Clifton Collge, Bristol

Peter Brook (All Round) Scholarship

09.2002 - 06.2007

A-Level: Maths: A, Physics: A, Chemistry: B

GCSE: $4 A^*, 5 A, 2 B$

SKILLS

Computer Programming

I have experience programming in a number of languages and environments. At University I program in Java, C, C++ and GNU Octave for projects ranging from multi-threaded servers to computer vision to digital signal processing. Outside of University, I work on websites and other projects using languages such as Python, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL.

I have great experience working with graphical languages such as Processing, and libraries such as openFrameworks as well as OpenGL and GLSL.

System Admistration

I run a Linux webserver and host websites for myself and friends, through this I am very comfortable in the UNIX shell and emacs editor.

Graphic Design

I have many years of experience with Adobe tools such as Photoshop and Illustrator. I can also comfortable in 3D environments such as Blender.

RECENT WORK

Visualising the London Underground

For a project in a graphics course at Univeristy, I visualised real Underground journeys published by Transport for London. I programmed this in OpenGL, where every journey was stored as a pixel in a buffer object and transformations were applied by the GPU using GLSL.

Fabricate

Fabricate, which is running my personal website, creates dynamic websites from text files, where 100% of the content is generated on the client side. Features include navigation via a command line and automatic pushing of content. It was made using JavaScript, Python and shell scripts.

Pedro & Sybil

For a second year project at University, I built and programmed a plotter (Pedro) and also wrote an accompanying piece of software to control it (Sybil). Full details, images, videos and code can be seen at: pedroandsybil.com. The plotter is controlled via a USB port on a laptop, where users can preview and manipulate the text/images before they are drawn. The software is native Mac OS X application programmed in C++/Objective-C using Cocoa and openFrameworks. The plotters firmware is programmed directly in C. All source code is open.

I recently won the first prize in the Goldsmiths Computing department art competition, my entry can be seen at wgallia.com#!adventuresinsine.

References

Dr. Mick Grierson, Tutor: m.grierson@gold.ac.ukDr. Marco Gillies, Tutor: m.gillies@gold.ac.uk

Andrew Shoben, greyworld: andrew@greyworld.org